A Guide to the Julia Sully Papers, 1854-1940
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Julia Sully Papers, 1854-1940
Library of Virginia
26567
1.35 cubic feet plus 1 oversized folder
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Donor information unavailable.
Biographical/Historical Information
Julia Sully (d. 1948) of Gordonsville, Virginia, was the great-grandniece of Thomas Sully, the distinguished painter, and grandaughter of Robert Sully, an eminent artist. She built a career around the arts, and was prominent in Richmond, Va., social and cultural life. She wrote a weekly column, entitled "The Camera and the Pen Recall Bygone Days: A Weekly Pictorial Series of Events and Places in Richmond's Past", for the RICHMOND NEWS LEADER during the mid-1930's, and served as director of the Art Index Division of the Virginia Commission on Conservation and Development from 1937-1940. She also served as chairman of the Richmond Branch of the Women's Organization for National Prohibition Reform in 1932.
Scope and Content Information
Papers, 1854-1940, of Julia Sully of Richmond, Virginia, including catalogs, clippings, correspondence, literary manuscripts, pamphlets, notes, and photographs. The majority of these papers are Sully's articles written for her weekly column "The Camera and the Pen Recall Bygone Days,", for the Richmond News Leader, on artists and their works, as they concerned Virginia. The newspaper copies of the articles are not included with these original typescripts.
Topics include the style of such artists as Thomas Eakins, George Fuller, Winslow Homer, Robert Mills, Claude Monet, Virginia's William L. Sheppard, Robert Sully, and Thomas Sully, the controversy over Mordi Gassner's murals on display at the Richmond Academy of Arts in 1936, Charles Hoffbauer's Confederate murals at the Confederate Memorial Institute, the Mariner's Museum in Newport News, Virginia, and an exhibition at the Richmond Academy of Arts for Leslie Bolling. Sully also wrote about the Frick collection of art in New York, John D. Rockefeller's folk art collection at William and Mary College, the artists of Spain and the Netherlands, and covered numerous openings at the Virginia Museum of Fine Arts in Richmond, Virginia.
Of note in the collection are materials relating to the Stone Mountain Confederate Memorial in Atlanta, Georgia. Included are correspondence and telegrams from the sculptor, Gutzon Borglum, to Julia Sully, regarding the controversy over the memorial which eventually led to Borglum's abandoning the project and destroying his models. Also included is a founders roll, an invitation to the unveiling of the Robert E. Lee carving in 1924, a report of the financial account with Borglum, a photograph of the memorial, and oversized editions of the Stone Mountain magazine, Volume 1, No. 3.
Another item of note are the collection of letters regarding Sully's work as chairman of the Richmond branch of the Women's Organization for National Prohibition Reform, 1932. These letters concern the organizations work with the Virginia Democratic party to repeal the eighteenth amendment of the Constitution.
Arrangement
Arranged alphabetically by folder title.
Contents List
- Bayeux Tapestry (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Bolling, Leslie (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Book of the Dead (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Cabell collection (Richmond, Va.) (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Clippings, 1919-1940 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Dutch art and artists, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Eakins, Thomas (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Fake art, 1935-1936 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Frick collection (NY, NY) (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Fuller, George (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Gassner, Mordi, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Hart, Joel (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Hoffbauer, Charles (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Hoffman, Malvina (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Homer, Winslow, 1936 May 15-17 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Hopkinson, Charles (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Huntington, Anna Hyatt (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Ironwork porches (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Japanese art and artists (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Jefferson, Thomas (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Jewish art and artists (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Joeutt, Matthew Harris, 1936 June 6 and 13 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- LaFarge, John, 1936 April 4 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Manship, Paul (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Mariners Museuem (Newport News, Va.), 1934-1936 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Mason, George (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Melchers, Gori (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Mellon collection (Washington, D.C.) (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Mills, Robert (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Miniatures (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Miscellaneous articles, lectures, etc., 1934 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Monet, Claude (Box 1, Folder 32)
- H. Sophie Newcomb Memorial College (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Notes, misc. (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Notes, misc. (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Notes, misc. (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Notes, misc. (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Notes, misc. (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Notes, misc. (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Notes, misc. (Box 2, Folder 7)
- John Payne collection (Richmond, Va.) (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Peale, C.W. (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Playing cards, 1934 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Portrait painters, 1936 February 15 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Printed material, 1914-1939 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Rembrandt (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Rockefeller collection (Williamsburg, Va.), 1935 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Saint-Memin, Charles (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Sheppard, William L., 1923 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Smibert, John, 1936 December 11 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Society of Washington Artists, 1936 March 25 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Spanish art and artists (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Statues, equestrian (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Stone Mountain Confederate Memorial (Atlanta, Ga.), 1923-1930 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Stuart, Gilbert (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Sully, Robert Matthew, 1854-1855 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Sully, Thomas, 1936 July 22 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Summer in Holland (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Vicarious research (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Virginia Historical Society, 1934 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Virginia Museum of Fine Arts- History (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Virginia Museum of Fine Arts- Opening, 1936 January 18 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Virginia Museum of Fine Arts- Romantic School Portrait Painters (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Walker, Duglad Stewart (Box 3, Folder 18)
- West, Benjamin (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Whistler, James Abbot McNeill (Box 3, Folder 20)
- White, Theodore (Box 3, Folder 21)
- William and Mary College- Portrait Library, 1935 (Box 3, Folder 22)
- Williamsburg, Va. (Box 3, Folder 23)
- Wollaston, John (Box 3, Folder 24)
- Women's Organization for National Prohibition Reform (Va.), 1932 (Box 3, Folder 25)
- Stone Mountain magazine, Volume 1, Number 3 (Folder Oversized folder)